A true adventure more erotic than any fantasy
Henry & June is a romance film directed by Philip Kaufman.
While traveling in Paris, author Henry Miller and his wife, June, meet Anais Nin, and
sexual sparks fly as Nin starts an affair with the openly bisexual June.
When June is forced to return to the U.S., she gives Nin
her blessing to sleep with her husband.
Then, when June returns to France, an unexpected, and
sometimes contentious, threesome forms.
Henry Miller, played by Fred Ward.
June Miller, played by Uma Thurman.
Anais Nin, played by Maria de Medeiros.
Richard Osborn, played by Kevin Spacey.
Jack, played by Bruce Myers.
Publisher, played by Juan Luis Buñuel.
Henry & June is a 1990 American biographical drama film directed by Philip
Kaufman, and starring Fred Ward, Uma Thurman, and Maria de Medeiros.
It is loosely based on the posthumously published 1986 Anaïs Nin book of the same name, and
tells the story of Nin's relationship with Henry Miller and his wife, June.
The film was nominated for Best Cinematography at the 63rd Academy Awards.
It was the first film to be given an NC-17 rating by the MPAA.
The film explores themes of paris, france, writer, polyamory, bohemian, 1930s.
The tone is emotional.